Guide to the Fanny Howe Papers, 1924-1993
Department of Special Collections
Fanny Howe Papers,
1924-1993
Special Collections M0648
Howe, Fanny.
8.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1993.
Biography
Fanny Howe was born into a distinguished Boston family in 1940. Her father, Mark De Wolf Howe, taught Law at Harvard University and was the first Charles Warren Professor in the History of American Law. He also was in the process of writing a multi-volume biography of Justice Oliver Wendall Holmes. At the time of his death in 1967 he had completed two volumes. Fanny Howe's mother, Mary Manning Howe, was born in Dublin, Ireland and had, during the time before she came to the United States, written and acted for the famous Abbey and Gate Theaters in Dublin. Fanny Howe has two sisters, Susan and Helen.
Scope and Content
The Fanny Howe papers contain correspondence, publications, notebooks and journals, family history, and material relating to Fanny Howe's career as a writer. The collection is divided into seven series, with series III - V representing all her written work, namely her poetry, short stories, and major literary publications. This collection was rearranged from the order it was received from Arundel Press.
Access Terms
Aldrich, Nelson W.; Armah, Ayi Kwei, 1939-; Armantrout, Rae, 1947-; Asner, Edward.; Auster, Paul, 1947-; Banks, Russell, 1940-; Beckett, Samuel, 1906-; Bellamy, Dodie.; Boone, Bruce.; Braverman, Melanie.; Childress, Alice.; Coolidge, Clark, 1939-; Corbett, William, 1942-; Creeley, Robert, 1926-; Dahlberg, Edward, 1900-1977.; Davis, Lydia.; Delafield, Fritz.; DeLillo, Don.; Equi, Elaine.; Fraser, Kathleen, 1937-; Gizzi, Peter.; Grenier, Robert.; Guest, Barbara.; Heaney, Seamus.; Hejinian, Lyn.; Howe, Fanny Quincy.; Howe, Helen.; Howe, Mark DeWolfe, 1906-1967.; Howe, Mary Manning.; Howe, Susan.; Levine, Philip, 1928-; Lowell, Robert, 1917-1977.; Mayer, Bernadette.; McCaffery, Steve.; McCall, Dan.; McCutcheon, Charles.; McCutcheon, Peter, d.1907.; McPherson, James.; Mailer, Norman.; Major, Clarence.; Marquand, John.; Mirskii, M. (Mark); Moran, Bob, 1931-; Morrow, Bradford, 1951-; Mus, David, 1936-; Owen, Maureen, 1943-; Palmer, Michael, 1942-; Payne, Johnny, 1958-; Ponsart, Emmanuel.; Read, Jay.; Rodefer, Stephen.; Rotenberg, Bettina.; Scalapino, Leslie.; Scott, Peter, 1962-; Senna, Carl, 1944-; Silliman, Ronald, 1946-; Simic, Charles, 1938-; Stein, Jean.; Stewart, Agnes.; Tate, James, 1943-; Valentine, Jean.; Walker, Alice, 1944-; Warsh, Lewis.; Watten, Barrett.; Wieners, John, 1934-; Young, Ferry Marquand.; American literature--20th century.; American poetry.; Poets, American.
Series Description
- Series I: Correspondence, 1935-1992
  Series I consists of correspondence both of a personal nature and of a business nature. The extent of the family correspondence is fairly significant. Fanny Howe kept much of the correspondence sent among family members, in particular between her father, Mark DeWolf Howe, and mother, Mary Manning, during the years 1935 to 1945. Also of note is the set of correspondence between Helen Howe (Mark DeWolf Howe's sister) and Fanny Quincy Howe (Mark DeWolf Howe's mother). This is important primarily because Fanny Howe, as a student in the writing program at MIT, submitted a proposal to write a biography of Mark DeWolf Howe and Helen Howe entitled Predictable Destitinies. Also of interest is Mark DeWolf's correspondence to Fanny Howe, 1957 - 1959, because much of the material contained in these letters would be used in one of Fanny Howe's writings entitled Ofay. Included in the general correspondence are Nelson Aldrich, Ed Asner, Russell Banks, Samuel Beckett, Robert Creeley, Robert Lowell, Norman Mailer, Bernadette Mayer, and May Sarton.
- Series II: Family/personal history
  Series II is a collection of material that relates to Fanny Howe's family and personal history. Included in this series are such items as Fanny's primary school results, her "autobiography" relating all the influences that affected her growth as a writer, an autobiography by Helen Huntington Howe entitled A Poor Innocent Young, and some photographs of Fanny. [Of note is material in Series I, box 3, folders 6 - 8 which corresponds to family history but, because of the order of material, could not be placed in Series II]
- Series III: Writings: poetry
  Series III, contains Fanny Howe's poetry, most of which has no collective title but is used for publications such as "Alsace-Lorraine," "Written in Eire," and "Eggs."
- Series IV: Literary manuscripts
  Series IV consists of Fanny Howe's literary manuscripts. These include Body and Soul, Bronte Wilde, Famous Questions, Reconstruction, Saving History, Un-American Activities, and material relating to The White Slave. [A text copy of Ofay is placed in Series VI because of the large size of the text]
- Series V: Writings: short stories, articles, reviews
  Series V contains school term papers, short stories, articles, and book reviews.
- Series VI. Miscellaneous
  Series VI contains miscellaneous material such as book reviews, plot summaries, and artwork for Howe's publications, along with publications by colleagues of Fanny Howe. Of mention in this series is "A Bernadette Mayer Reader" which contains the poetry of Bernadette Mayer. Also included is a copy of the text Ofay and the layout design for Robeson Street.
- Series VII: Personal notebooks/journals (ca. 1959 - 1992)
  Series VII consists of the notebooks and journals kept by Fanny Howe. The majority of these notebooks contain personal entries, poetry, short stories, and outlines, including original manuscripts for the publications Bronte Wilde and Saving History. One notebook contains the original format to the work Reconstruction.
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1935-1992
  - Aldrich, Jr., Nelson (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alexander, Charles (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Armah, Ayi Kwei (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Armantrout, Rae (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Asner, Ed (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Auster, Paul (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Banks, Russell (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Beckett, Samuel (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bellamy, Dodie (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Boone, Bruce (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Braverman, Melanie (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bretton, Coburn (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Castro, Jan Garden (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Childress, Alice (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Coolidge, Clark (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Corbett, William (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Creeley, Robert (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dahlberg, Edward (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Davis, Lydia (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Delafield, Fritz (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - DeLillo, Don (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Equi, Elaine (El) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Forrest ? (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Fraser, Kathleen (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Gizzi, Peter (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Gleichman, Gabi & Lee (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Grenier, Bob (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Guest, Barbara (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Heaney, Seamus (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Hejinian, Lyn (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - High, John (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Howe, Fanny (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Howe, Helen (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Howe, Mark DeWolf (to Fanny Howe): originals (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - -------: xeroxed copies (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Howe, Mark DeWolf (to Mary Manning Howe, 1935) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - -------, (1936-37) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - -------, (1943) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - -------, (1944) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - -------, (1945) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Howe, Mary Manning (1957 - 1967) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - -------, (1968 - 1976) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - -------, (1977 - 1979) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - -------, (ND) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - -------, (Incoming only - Most re. husband's death) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Howe, Quincy (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Howe, Quincy Sr. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Howe, Susan (Sukey): 1957 - 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - -------, 1968 - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - -------, ND (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Howe, Tina (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Marquand Young, Ferry (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Howe, Fanny Quincy (to Helen Howe) - photocopies (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - ------- (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ------- (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - ------- (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - ------- (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Proposal: "Predictable Destinies: a biography of Mark Howe and Helen Howe" (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Helen Howe's Diary, 5/23/28 - 11/18/29 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Inventory of Howe Collection & miscellaneous excerpts (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Howe, Helen (to Fanny Quincy Howe) - photocopies (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - ------- (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - ------- (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - ------- (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - ------- (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - ------- (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Howe, Helen (Mrs. Reginald Allen) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - International Poetry Society (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Janeway, Mike (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Levine, Philip (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Lovell, Thoreau (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Lowell, Robert (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Luckes, Flo (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - McCaffery, Steve (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - McCall, Dan (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - McCutcheon, Charles (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - McMillan, George (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - McPherson, James (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Mailer, Norman (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Major, Clarence (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Marquand, John (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Marquand Young, Ferry (See Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mayer, Bernadette (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Melnyczuk, Askold (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mirsky, Mark (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Moran, Bob (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Morrow, Brad (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Mus, David (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Myrow, F. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Owen, Maureen (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Palmer, Michael (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Payne, Johnny (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Ponsart, Emmanuel (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Read, Jay (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Rodefer, Stephen (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Ronk, Martha (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Rotenberg, Bettina (Tina) (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Sarton, May (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Scalapino, Leslie (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Scott, Peter (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Sherman, Ken (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Silliman, Ron (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Simic, Charles (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Sisler, William P. (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Stein, Jean (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Stewart, Agnes (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Tate, James (includes poetry and photographs) (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Valentine, Jean (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Walker, Alice (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Warsh, Lewis (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Watten, Barrett (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Wieners, John (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Wienreb, Lloyd L. (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Unknown (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Series II: Family/personal history
  - Autobiography: family and literary influences (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - A Poor Innocent Young, xeroxed typed MS (pp. 1 - 73) by Helen Huntington Howe (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - -------, (pp. 74 - 146a) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Helen Howe biography (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "The Reminiscences of Quincy Howe," interview, 1962 (title page - p. 65) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - -------, (pp. 66 - 129) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Buckingham School & Beaver County Day School Report Cards, 1945 - 1957 (Fanny Howe) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Memorial material regarding Mark DeWolf Howe (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: Fanny Howe (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous papers: Howe's curriculum vitae; personal notes; magazine articles (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Series III: Writings: poetry
  - Miscellaneous poems (a) - No collective title (prose poems incl.) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - ------- (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - ------- (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - ------- (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - -------, incl. "Alsace-Lorraine," "Measure of Pleasure," and "Torn Parts: A Novel" (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - ------- (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous poems (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - ------- (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - ------- (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ------- (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - ------- (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - ------- (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ------- (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ------- (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Eggs," - Poetry, 2/27/70 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "The Vineyard" (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "De Ultima Die" (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "Alsace-Lorraine,", xeroxed MS (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "When She Was Dying" (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "Written in Eire" (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "The Water Gardens at Glan" and "Written in Eire" (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "Written in Eire" (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "Perfume Burned on a Stick" (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - "Democracy" (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "Metaxu" (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Prose poetry (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Series IV: Literary manuscripts
  - Body and Soul - original draft, 11/89 (title page - p. 70) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - -------, (pp. 71 - 140) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - -------, (pp. 141 - 212) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - -------, (title page - p. 70) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - -------, (pp. 71 - 140) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - -------, (pp. 141 - 214) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bronte Wilde, xerox copy (title page - p. 75) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - -------, (pp. 76 - 153) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - -------, incomplete (pp. 10 - 75) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - -------, (pp. 76 - 153) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - -------, entire piece with corrections (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Famous Questions, xeroxed original, 12/86 (a) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - -------, (b) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - -------, (c) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - -------, typed MS (title page - p.68) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - -------, (pp. 69 - 140) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - -------, (pp. 141 - 192) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - -------, xeroxed typed MS (title page - p. 70) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - -------, (pp. 71 - 137) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Plot summary: Famous Questions (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Reconstruction: entire MS, with corrections (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - -------, (title page - p. 100) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - -------, (pp. 101 - end) no order to pages (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Plot summary: Saving History (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Saving History, xeroxed typed MS (title page - p.75) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - -------, (pp. 76 - 157) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - -------, (title page - p. 115) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - -------, (pp. 116 - 228) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - -------, (pp. 6 - 115) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - -------, (pp. 116 - 220), incomplete (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - -------, Xerox proof copy (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - -------, premise (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous excerpts from Saving History & Bronte Wilde (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Un-American Activities, (title page - p. 79) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - -------, (pp. 80 - 160) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - -------, (pp. 161 - 243) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - The White Slave: Correspondence, news clippings, and "The White Slave: The Story of Peter McCutcheon" by Charles McCutcheon (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - The White Slave: Publishing Rights with Avon Books (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Series V: Writings: short stories, articles, reviews
  - Early Writings for Children (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "More Sinned Against Than Sinning" (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "He Whom We Must Love Is Absent" (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "The End" (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "Why I Protest" (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "A Way Through the Fields" (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "The Contemporary Logos" (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Article: "Media Mamas: The Single Ones" (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "Eathwork or Earthworks" (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Wheels and Wings" (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Notes on the Nouveau Pauvre" (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "Lost AND" dialogue (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "Blind Tiger: A Meditation" (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "Mr. Hood" (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "The Latecomer," "Crazy Words and a Swift Illusion," "All Black" (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "A Distortion of Rain," "Your Loving Daughter" (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "The Reverend's Daughter," "The Congenital Trap," "Shrill Confessions" (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "Tremendum," "The Forerunner," "With Respect to a Sister's Dream" (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - "Antagony of Hell" (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - "The Golden Touch of Nathaniel Hawthorne" (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - "An Interview with Alexander Theroux" (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - No title: practice of letter writing (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - "Ecstatic Aesthetics" (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - "What Nobody Saw" (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - "Progressive Cutting," "Work with Leacock" (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - "The Am Track," "Shot in a Little Town" (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "The Snow Association" (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - "Onset" (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - "Radio Play" (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - "Bees of the Invisible" (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - "Apollo in the Ring," "Two Particles from the Land of Plenty" (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "D'Ye Ken John Peel?" "Role of Innocence in Wuthering Heights" (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - "Under the Weather," "The Ring of Birches" (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - "Pluto in Lethe," "One New Years Day," "The Ice Palace" (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - "The Edge of Darkness," "Taking the Train," "Thief" (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - "The Last Virgin," "Celia's Metamorphoses" (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Untitles Stories; Incomplete Stories (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Various Stories: Untitled (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Writings: "The Cruelties," "The Broken Word," "The Shades of Hell," "Abstract Hells," (partial texts) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Anais Nin Article (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Book Reviews by Fanny Howe (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - ------- (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - ------- (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - ------- (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous
  - Book reviews re. Howe's publications (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - The Fiction Collective (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - The Atlantic Monthly (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Original watercolor/pen/ink illustrations for In the Middle of Nowhere (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Original artwork (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "First Marriage," artwork (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Plot summary: Jamaica Plain (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Plot summary: One Crossed Out (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Howe's publications: synopsis of each (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "A Bernadette Mayer Reader" (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - ------- (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - "The Highlands": memorandum and plot summary (corrections by Fanny Howe) (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - "Five Poems," by Elaine Equi (signed) (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - "Passion Come Running," poems by Philip Good (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - "Everything I Always Wanted For You," Screenplay: based on story "Dump Gull" (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - "The lives of thomas: episodes & prayers," by john high (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Avon Books copyright agreement; Copyright registration (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous flyers and reviews (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Ofay (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Layout design for Robeson Street (Oversize 13)
- Series VII: Personal notebooks/journals (ca. 1959 - 1992)
  - Notebook: "The Introduction to the Future," dated June-October, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Notebook: "Erebus and Terror," original MS of Bronte Wilde with miscellaneous poetry (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Light green notebook: poetry, "Descriptions without Implications" (incl. 1 loose page entitled "It's Always Like This") (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - UCSD notebook: Original MS of Saving History (partial?) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: "Sabbatical, 1990" (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: diary, ca. 1991 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    ("Aug. 5: Drove to NYC, after.. .)
  - Notebook: "The Rock Island Scrolls" or "First Marriage," (original MS) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: original MS, unknown (incl. 8 loose pages) (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Green notebook (civic duplicate book): Diary (June 19, We moved out to Sandycove today.. .) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Blue notebook: "The Father and the Ghost: a Heresy"; miscellaneous notes (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Loose pages removed from above Blue notebook (Box 15, folder 2) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: (All in the past, I tramped... .) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: short stories and poems, incl. "Persophone and Pluto" and Hydraulics and Horse" (incl. 2 loose pages) (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Red notebook: "I'd been almost a Communist when.. .) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Light blue notebook: "About the Children," May 11, 1976 and an untitled script (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Black marbled notebook: (7/23) Miscellaneous personal entries, poems (incl. 1 loose page) (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Notebook: personal entries (incl. 8 loose pages) (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Reconstruction: original layout (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Notebook: poetry, quotations, notes (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Gray notebook (Fanny Howe signature top right): personal entries, (incl. 7 loose pages) (Box 15, Folder 12)